Guide to the Duke University Equestrian Team (DUET) records, 1977-1981
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Duke University Equestrian Team (DUET) records 1977-1981
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Equestrian Team.
0.5 Linear Feet 500 Items
The Duke University Equestrian Team (DUET) was formed in 1976 to provide a means for equestrians to represent Duke University in competitions.
Records contain correspondence, programs, reports, financial materials, agendas, membership lists, minutes, a charter application, a constitution, and notebooks. Major subjects include Duke University, sports clubs, horse showing in the southeastern United States, intercollegiate sports, and the Duke University Equestrian Team. Materials range in date from 1977 to 1981.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Duke University Equestrian Team records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980.
Historical Note
from: http://www.ihsa.com
The Duke University Equestrian Team (DUET) was formed in 1976 to provide a means for equestrians to represent Duke University in competitions. During the 1970s-1980s, membership was open to all Duke University undergraduates and Equestrian Team Alumni, both men and women. During its first four years, the team participated in about six events annually. The club was funded by dues, fundraisers, and ASDU allowances.
The Duke University Equestrian Team participates in the Intercollegiate Horse Show Association (IHSA), an association of student teams from all over the United States. The IHSA promotes competition for riders of all skill levels, who compete individually and as teams at regional and national levels. The competitions are unique in that no rider may use his or her own horse; all horses are supplied by the college hosting the event. During the early 1980s, the team participated in IHSA competitions at James Madison University, Southern Seminary Junior College, and Randolph Macon Woman's College.
Since the 1980s, the Duke University team has had about 15-20 members per year. As of 2007, the Duke University Equestrian Team is active.
Collection Overview
Contains materials pertaining to the Duke University Equestrian Team. Materials range date from 1977 to 1981.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- Sports
Duke University -- Students
Duke University. Equestrian Team
Horsemanship -- North Carolina -- Durham
Horse shows
Intercollegiate Horse Show Association
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1978-1980
  - Constitution, undated
  - Financial materials, circa 1979-1980
  - Notebooks containing meeting notes, scores, schedules, 1979-1980, 1980-1981
  - Agendas and minutes, 1978-1980
  - Membership lists, 1977-1979
  - Charter application for club recognition, to Associated Students of Duke University, 1980
  - General office duties, 1978
  - Club Sports guidance, 1978-1980
  - Competitions and shows, announcements and summaries, 1977-1979
  - Competitions and shows, announcements and summaries, 1979-1981